Carl W. Ackerman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1909-1964 (Box 159-193)
  - Articles (Box 166)
    - "The Black Flags of Hungary," Saturday Evening Post, 17 July 1917
    - "The Submarine Post Office," Saturday Evening Post, 11 Aug. 1917
    - "Pigs and Victory," Saturday Evening Post, 25 Aug. 1917
    - "Germany, the Next Republic?" published serially in Philadelphia Evening Ledger, Sept.-Oct. 1917
    - "The War of Words," Saturday Evening Post, 8 Sept. 1917
    - "Mexico-Enemy or Ally?" Saturday Evening Post, 15 Sept. 1917
    - "Rebels and Revolution," Saturday Evening Post, 22 Sept. 1917
    - "Rising or Setting Sun in Mexico?" Saturday Evening Post, 6 Oct. 1917
    - Letter concerning articles by Charles W. Eliot and H. G. Wells, Philadelphia Evening Ledger, 13 Oct. 1917
    - "The Last Spy Offensive," Saturday Evening Post, 10 Nov. 1917
    - "United We Win" Lessons from the German Drive," Saturday Evening Post, 1 Dec. 1917
    - "The Coming Disaster," Saturday Evening Post, 29 Dec. 1917
    - "Germany's Last Trump," Saturday Evening Post, 2 Mar. 1918
    - "The Nightmare of Peace," Saturday Evening Post, 9 Mar. 1918
    - "The U-Boats off Spain," Saturday Evening Post, 18 Mar. 1918
    - "Tales of the Refugees," Saturday Evening Post, 23 Mar. 1918
    - "Fighting for a Free Press," Saturday Evening Post, 6 Apr. 1918
    - "Making Flanders Goose-Step," Saturday Evening Post, 13 Apr. 1918
    - "The Street Parliaments," Saturday Evening Post, 27 Apr. 1918
    - "Reform or Revolution," Saturday Evening Post, 4 May 1918
    - "The Omnipotent Five," Saturday Evening Post, 18 May 1918
    - "Bolsheviking the Swiss," Saturday Evening Post, 25 May 1918
    - "The Whirlwind in Austria," Saturday Evening Post, 15 June 1918
    - "Germany's Policy in Russia," Saturday Evening Post, 17 Aug. 1918
    - Articles for the Philadelphia Evening Ledger, Aug. 1918
    - "The Lusitania Aftermath: What Will the German Navy Do?" Saturday Evening Post, 14 Sept. 1918
      - Correspondence
        - Daniels, Josephus
    - Articles for the Saturday Evening Post (Box 170)
      - Miscellany, 1917-1918
    - Articles written from Siberia for the New York Times Oct.
      - Oct. 1918-Jan. 1919
      - Miscellaneous typescripts, Oct. 1918-Jan. 1919
    - Copies of dispatches cabled to the New York Times from Siberia, Oct. 1918-Jan. 1919
    - Interview with the President of China, New York Times, 17 Jan. 1919
    - "Diary Record of Tsar's Last Days," Japan Advertiser, 23 Jan. 1919
    - "Civilization a Mockery in the Rusia of Today" and "Across Siberia from Vladivostok," New York Times, 26 Jan. 1919
    - "Is the Czar Dead?" New York Times Magazine, 23 Feb. 1919
    - "China and the League of Nations," New York Times, 2 Mar. 1919 (Box 171)
    - "Trouble With Japan Averted Before the Armistice," New York Times, 16 Mar. 1919
    - "Japan's Ambitions in Siberia," Current History, Apr. 1919
    - "Co-operative Unions Halt the Bolsheviki," New York Times, 18 May 1919
    - Articles for the Philadelphia Public Ledger syndicate, 1919
    - Articles for the Philadelphia Public Ledger Foreign News Service (Box 172)
      - Jan. 1920-June 1921
      - Scrapbooks, Feb. 1920-May 1921 (Box 173)
    - "Inside of Irish Parley," New York Times, 7 Aug. 1921
    - Amos A. Fries, "The Future of Poison Gas," Current History, Dec. 1921
    - "Keep the Home Stacks Smoking," Columbia, Mar. 1922
    - "Ireland From a Scotland Yard Notebook" (Box 174)
      - Atlantic Monthly
        - Part 1, Apr. 1922
        - Part 2, "The Irish Education of Mr. Lloyd George," May 1922
        - Part 3, "Janus-Headed Ireland," June 1922
    - "How the President Keeps Well," Saturday Evening Post, 5 May 1923
      - Notes
      - Typescript edited by Warren G. Harding
    - "Russia and Japan Manoeuvring for Basis of New Partnership," New York Times, 1 July 1923
    - Editorials for Advertising Club News, July-Aug. 1923
    - "Recovering Gold From Smoke," Journal of the American Bankers Association, Aug. 1923
    - "The Dream of Ireland's Lincoln," Hearst's International, 1923
    - "How My Wife Has Helped Me," letter to New York Telegram and Evening Mail, 16 May 1924
    - "The Sheik Should Stay on the Farm," Toledo News-Bee, June 1926
    - "Responsibility in Journalism," North American Review, 1931
    - "George Eastman, Benefactor of Education,"
      - Technology Review, Apr. 1932
        - Correspondence
          - Eastman, George
          - Killian, J. Rhyne, Jr.
    - "Looking Ahead," Columbia Journalist, 1932
    - "To Robert Underwood Johnson," The Earlhamite, Jan. 1933 (Box 175)
    - "Balancing the Newspaper Budget" and "The Newspaper in International Affairs," Emory University Bulletin, Mar. 1933
    - "Students Under the 'New Deal,'" Columbia Journalist, 1934
    - "The Press at the Hauptmann Trial," Hunterdon County Democrat, 31 Jan. 1935
    - "Public Opinion and Peace," Philippines Herald, 16 Nov. 1935
    - Statement, Columbia Journalist, 1935
    - "Free Trade in International News," Sanj Vartaman Annual, Bombay, India, 1937
    - "Anniversary," Independent Journal of Columbia University, 1937
    - "Pulitzer Prizes for the Cinema," Cinema Arts, July 1937
    - "How the Government Dominates Business and the Press," Public Relations, Apr. 1938
    - "'Marse Henry' Up to Date," Letter to the editor, New York Times, 4 May 1939
    - "Rethinking Education," Talks, Apr. 1939
    - "Journalism," The Idol, Union College, Schenectady, N.Y., 17 Nov. 1939
    - "Psalm of America," Cathedral Age, Spring 1940
    - "Vital Relation of News to Global Peace,"
      - Everybody's Weekly section of Philadephia Inquirer, 14 Feb. 1943
    - "How University Journalism Course Operates in United States of America," The Newspaper World, 27 Jan. 1945
    - "United Nations and a United Church: Essentials for a New World Order," The Churchman, 15 Sept. 1946
    - "Is Political Conformity Forced Upon Students?" (Box 176)
      - Bulletin of the American Society of Newspaper Editors, 1 Apr. 1953
      - Correspondence and clipping book
        - Bliss, Robert Woods
        - Fulbright, J. William
        - Grew, Joseph C.
        - Kennan, George (b. 1904)
        - Lamont, Corliss
        - Pringle, Henry F.
    - "The Desire To Live," The Leaflet of St. John's Church, Washington, 24 Jan. 1954
    - "Newspapers and Civic Responsibility in a Crisis," Vicksburg Sunday Post-Herald, 30 Sept. 1956
    - "Laughing Gas for People Over 65?" Lifetime Living, Sept. 1956
    - Articles for the Dothan Eagle, 1962
    - "Pioneering in Journalism," Journalists in Action, 1963 (Box 177)
    - Review of Raymond Swing's Good Evening, 1964
    - Article, Dothan Eagle, 1964
    - "On the Line," guest column for Bob Considine, undated
  - Books
    - Germany, the Next Republic? 1917
      - Correspondence
      - Galley proof
      - Notes (Box 178)
      - Reviews, notices
    - Mexico's Dilemma, 1918
      - Correspondence
      - Reviews, notices
    - “A Vision of Victory: Germany in the Fifth Year of the War” (unpublished), fragments, 1918
    - Trailing the Bolsheviki, 1919 (Box 179)
      - Galley proof
      - Illustration
      - Miscellany
      - Reviews, notices
    - Dawes, the Doer! 1924 (Box 180)
      - Correspondence
      - Reviews, notices
    - “The Art of Management” (unpublished book for General Motors Corp.), 1930
      - Correspondence
      - Outline and notes
      - Miscellany
    - “Newspapers in Public Affairs” (unpublished), 1934 (Box 181)
      - Miscellany
      - Typescript
    - George Eastman, 1930
      - Correspondence
        - Burkhart, Harvey J.
        - Eastman, George
        - Flexner, Abraham
        - House, Edward Mandell
        - Hutchison, Alice K.
        - Scaife, Roger L.
        - Seligman, Edwin R. A.
      - Miscellany (Box 182)
      - Notes, drafts
      - First draft (typescript) (Box 183)
      - Research material, (1 folder) (Box 184, Box 185)
      - Reviews, notices
      - Translation into Chinese (excerpts)
      - "The Evolution of Chemical Research in Industry in the United States" (unpublished appendix) (Box 186)
        - Correspondence
        - Typescripts
      - "Mr. Smith" (unpublished chapter)
    - “The Right Road to Peace” (unpublished), 1945
    - “Eisenhower in Wonderland” (unpublished), 1956-1957 (Box 187)
      - Typescripts, 1957
        - Miscellaneous drafts
        - Original draft
        - Final draft
      - Correspondence (Box 188)
        - Bohemian Club, San Francisco, Calif.
        - Byrnes, James F.
        - Esberg, Milton H., Jr.
        - Hillman, William
        - Solbert, Oscar N.
      - Correspondence with publishers
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous
      - Research notes and drafts, 1956-1957
        - Bohemian Club, San Francisco, Calif.
        - Early history of Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
        - Eisenhower, Mamie
        - Freeman, Douglas Southall
        - Future of Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
        - "The lighter side," clippings
        - "Shh! This Is Columbia" demonstration, Oct. 1940
      - Miscellaneous research notes
      - Miscellaneous research notes and drafts (Box 189)
      - Miscellaneous printed matter and clippings used in research
  - Reports, Columbia University, New York, N.Y. (Box 190)
    - Report of the Dean of the School of Journalism
      - 1932-1935, (4 folders)
    - Public Opinion Around the World: A Report by Dean Carl W. Ackerman of the Graduate School of Journalism, 19 Dec. 1936
    - Report of the Dean of the Graduate School of Journalism
      - 1936-1937, (2 folders)
      - Supplement, 1937: The Black Plague of the Twentieth Century
        - Correspondence, 1937-1938
        - Miscellany, 1937-1938
      - 1938 (Box 191)
      - Supplement: The Refuge of World Opinion
      - 1939-1943, (5 folders)
    - The Chinese Post-Graduate School of Journalism, Mar. 1943-Aug. 1945: Report of the Dean of the Graduate School of Journalism
    - One Million for the Advancement of Journalism, 1948
    - Gist, Sept. 1950 (annual report of the Dean of the Graduate School of Journalism)
    - Annual report, 1951, typescript (Box 192)
    - The Dawn of the XXI Century, 1955
  - Miscellaneous writings; unpublished and unidentified typescripts
    - "Interview with Count von Bernstorff," 8 Jan. 1914
    - "In 1849 Victor Hugo Prophesied a United States of Europe," circa 1914
    - "The War and Our Next Election," circa 1914
    - "Uncle Sam and the War," Jan. 1915
    - "Methods and Organization of the Censorship in Germany," 1 May 1917
    - "Spy or Die; Scenario of a Five-act Play on Germany," 1917
    - "The Bear of Pontarlier," spy story, 1918
    - "The New American Ambassador: Colonel George Brinton McClellan Harvey, LL.D.," 1921
    - "Reporting for the Main Street Journal," outline of proposed book, circa 1921
    - "Gooding Has the 'Goods,'" American Valuation Association, circa 1925
    - "The Prophecy of the Vicar of Greenwich," 1927
    - "Our Economic Hereafter," circa 1927
    - Statement, "The Press and World Peace," 1931
    - Introduction to Headlines and Deadlines, 1933
    - Statement, "The Freedom of the Press," 15 Aug. 1933
    - Statement, American Society of Newspaper Editors, Report of the Committee on the Press and Public Relations, Washington, 19-21 Apr. 1934
    - Statement on transition to a graduate school of journalism, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1935
    - "Decision of the United States Supreme Court in the Louisiana Tax Case," submitted to the New York Times, Feb. 1936
    - "The New Deal Abroad," circa 1936
    - "Journalism in the United States," 4 May 1939
    - "Periodismo en los Estados Unidos," 4 May 1939
    - Statement, "The End of World Wars," 30 Mar. 1940
    - Open letter to Dr. Samuel Harden Church, 2 May 1940
    - "Letter to the Press and Radio," uncirculated, 22 May 1940
    - Round robin letter to students, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1 Jan. 1942
    - Introduction to David Hinshaw's Journalism-Today's Third Estate, 1943
    - "Mexican Russian, and British Activities in Latin America," 1944
    - "The Greater Miracles," 1954
    - Notes for article for This Week magazine, 1956
    - "Pulitzer Prizes Versus Ivy League Colleges," outline of unpublished article
    - "The Baby Plague in Germany," by Mabel VanderHoof Ackerman (Box 193)
    - "14 Points for the Mellon Plan"
    - "Germany Is Preparing Another Peace Drive"
    - "The Molder"
    - "Poison Gas and the Washington Conference"
    - "Scarlet Letters"
    - "Scarlet Letters of Suspicion"
    - "Vagabonding in Siberia; the Pot Puri of Russia"
    - Miscellaneous typescripts concerning China, 1918-1919 (fragments)
    - Miscellaneous typescripts concerning Germany, 1914-1918 (fragments)
    - Miscellaneous typescripts concerning Russia and Siberia, 1918-1919 (fragments)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified typescripts (fragments)
    - Card index to writings, 1928-1956
- Miscellany, 1833-1970 (Box 194-227)
  Newspaper clippings, printed matter, and miscellaneous personal papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Ackerman, Carl W., miscellaneous clippings and printed matter concerning (Box 194)
    - 1913-1935
    - 1936-1970, undated (Box 195)
  - Anecdotes
  - Awards See also Oversize
  - Birthday souvenirs
  - Calling cards
  - Certificates See also Oversize
  - Charitable appeals received
  - Christmas cards sent
  - Clippings
    - 1893-1909
    - 1911-1914 (Box 196)
    - 1915-1917 (Box 197)
    - 1918-1919 (Box 198)
    - 1919-1932 (Box 199)
    - 1933-1937 (Box 200)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 201)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 202)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 203)
    - 1940 (Box 204)
    - 1941 (Box 205)
    - 1942 (Box 206)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 207)
    - 1943-1945 (Box 208)
    - 1945 (Box 209)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 210)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 211)
    - 1948-1950 (Box 212)
    - 1951-1969, undated (Box 213)
  - Degrees (Box 214)
  - Employment proposals
  - Financial papers
    - 1914-1918
    - 1919-1921 (Box 215)
    - 1922-1929 (Box 216)
    - 1930-1938 (Box 217)
    - 1939-1947 (Box 218)
    - 1948-1952 (Box 219)
    - 1953-1955 (Box 220)
    - 1956-1970, undated (Box 221)
  - Invitations (Box 222)
  - Jackson, Andrew; Edward Livingston; and Roger B. Taney, signed patent letters, 18 Feb. 1833
  - Licenses, permits
  - Medical papers
  - Memberships
  - Memoranda
  - Press credentials
  - Printed matter (Box 223)
    - 1911-1929
    - 1935-1954 (Box 224)
    - 1962-1964, undated (Box 225)
  - Programs, menus (Box 226)
  - Quotations
  - Sketches
  - Student papers, circa 1904-1913, undated (Box 227)
  - Tickets
  - Travel documents
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers
    - Passports, visas
  - Unidentified papers
- Oversize (Box 228)
  Awards, certificates, and related miscellany.
  Organized according to the series and container from which the material was removed.
  - Miscellany (Box 228)
    - Awards, certificates, and other miscellany (Container 195)
- Classified (Box CL1)
  Classified item described according to the series, file, and container from which it was removed.
  - Subject File (Box CL 1)
    - China, Republic of
      - Post-Graduate School of Journalism, 1943-1945 (Container 63)